shutterpoint.com 2012-11-18

# Privacy Policy - ShutterPoint Stock Photography

ShutterPoint.com is committed to maintaining the privacy of information that you provide to us when using our website. This Privacy Policy describes what information we gather, how we use it, and how our members can correct or change it. 

To jump to a particular section, use links below: 

  * Membership Information
  * IP Addresses, Cookies and Log Files
  * Surveys
  * Your Privacy at Other Sites
  * Opting Out
  * Notification of Changes

## Membership Information

In order to be a member of this website, you have to complete the registration form. During registration users are asked to give their personally identifiable information (such as name, age range, e-mail address). We may use the e-mail address information to send the reminders of upcoming storage space subscription expiration or running low on space reminders; notifications about our new or existing products and services, special offers, or to otherwise contact you regarding your account with us. During registration you are asked to create a unique username that will be required for gaining access to the member-only features of this webiste. Your username is not treated as personally identifiable information and may be shown on this website in connection with the albums(s) you may choose to create and maintain. Additionally, your first and last name will be shown on this website in connection with the albums(s) you may choose to create and maintain or in connection to the public member directory. Your e-mail address is never displayed anywhere at this website and it cannot be obtained by other users of this website. Additionally, your e-mail is never given, rented or sold to any third parties. 

In the very rare cases, we also may use your first name, last name and username in the promotional or marketing purposes. It is optional for the user to provide demographic information (such as age range, gender and similar information), but encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our site.  We may share the demographic information with third parties, such as researchers, but only in the form of aggregated data.  This helps us and our partners understand our member demographics, and is essential and critical to improving our services. 

We do not share, sell or rent information about individual users with any third party at any time, except: 

  * When you specifically authorize us to or request that we do so.
  * When we believe that such action is necessary to comply with the law or legal process.

At any time after registration, members can change all information they provided (with the exception of the username) by visiting the My Information page under the My Account area of our website. 

## IP Addresses, Cookies and Log Files

Cookies are small files that our site places on the hard drive of your computer to enable us to customize your experience and achieve some of the site's functionality. While on our website, usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information. Cookies are the very common mechanism used by major sites on the Internet. Visitors may also receive cookies from third parties, including advertisers, but ShutterPoint.com cannot have any control of the content of these cookies. Please note that should you choose to refuse cookies on this website, some of its functionality will be forfeited and some portions of the site may become unusable. 

We use your IP address to analyze trends, administer the site and help determine problems with the servers. We may also automatically log IP addresses to track a user's session, ratings, comments and purchases. IP addresses themselves are not linked to personally identifiable information, however they may be linked to a member's account records. 

## Surveys

We may occasionally conduct online surveys to better target our offering to our audience.  We may share any demographic data collected during these surveys with our partners, but only in the form of aggregated information.  We will not share any information about specific individuals gathered during a survey with third parties. Please remember that your participation is optional and helps us improve our services. 

## Your Privacy at Other Sites

ShutterPoint.com contains many links to other sites in the form of text links or banners.  ShutterPoint.com is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites.  We recommend that you review the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.  
This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by this website. 

## Opting Out

You may request that we delete your membership and accompanying member information at any time. You also may choose not to become a member and not to participate in the "member-only" areas of our site, this eliminates the need for you to give us any personal information at all. 

## Notification of Changes

This policy can be updated on the as-needed basis and without prior notice.  If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on our website.  If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify our members by way of an e-mail.
